# clean tags from a file
sed 's/<[^>]*>//g' file.xml

# remove lines from a file containing two consequent ocurrences of tab spaces
sed '/\t\t/d' file.txt

# remove all URLS from file
sed -e 's!http[s]\?://\S*!!g' big_corpus_blogs.txt > big_corpus_blogs_no_urls.txt

# find overlapping named-entities
grep -oP '<[A-Z]+>[^<]+<[A-Z]+>[^<]+</[A-Z]+>[^<]+</[A-Z]+>' nyt_eng_199411.txt.tagged

# clean publico crawled news articles
cat publico-all.txt | sed s/".*\t"/""/g | sed s/"['\"\(\)\`”′″‴«»„”]"/""/g | sed s/"--"/"-"/g | sed s/"\([.,;]\)"/" \1 "/g | sed s/"  "/" "/g | sed s/"[.\!?] *\([A-Z]\)"/"\n\1"/g | sed s/"\(\w\)[\.,;\!?\"]"/"\1 "/g | sed s/"  "/" "/g > input.pt.txt

# replace long tags with short tags, e.g., <ORGANIZATION> to <ORG>
cat annotations/sentences_uniq_random.txt | sed 's/<ORGANIZATION>/<ORG>/g' | sed 's/<\/ORGANIZATION>/<\/ORG>/g' | sed 's/<PERSON>/<PER>/g' | sed 's/<\/PERSON>/<\/PER>/g' | sed 's/<LOCATION>/<LOC>/g' | sed 's/<\/LOCATION>/<\/LOC>/g'

# add tag to a string in a file
sed 's/ Facebook / <ORG>Facebook<\/ORG> /g' sentences_matched_freebase.txt > sentences_matched_freebase2.txt
